<doc docid='harvard_3' lang='eng' type='mono' source_url='https://drive.google.com/open?id=1R74zS6G8BmewK_CFpPuOvwdRBKiHzryg'>
<p>
Prevent the spread of COVID-19
</p>
<p>
Stay home whenever you can, except to get medical care! 
Stay at least six feet from other people, even if they don’t look ill. 
Find out what your community’s policies are regarding leaving your home.
</p>
<p>
Wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds.
Do so before you eat or prepare food, and after you sneeze, cough, blow your nose, or visit any public place. 
If you cannot wash with soap andwater, use hand sanitizer containing at least 60% alcohol.
</p>
<p>
Avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth.
The virus can last on some surfaces for several days.
You can become infected if you touch these surfaces and then touch your eyes, nose, or mouth.
</p>
<p>
Clean and disinfect frequently touched surfaces.
Using alcohol solutions that contain at least 70% alcohol, or diluted household bleach solutions, clean frequently used objects like phones, keys, tablets, doorknobs, and TV remotes.
</p>
<p>
Cover coughs and sneezes with a tissue or your elbow.
Coronavirus is primarily spread through droplets when an infected person coughs or sneezes near others. 
Do not cough or sneeze into your hand.
</p>
<p>
Plan how to take care of yourself and loved ones.
Older adults and people with chronic medical conditions are at higher risk and should consult with doctors about staying protected. 
Create a list of emergency contacts and designate space in your home for sick family members.
</p>
<p>
The DO’s and DON’Ts of prevention
DO
Stay home, except to get medical care. 
If you have severe symptoms, call 911.
Wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds (or use hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol).
Cover your coughs and sneezes with your elbow or sleeve.
Stay informed by visiting the COVID-19 website of your local health department, the CDC, and the WHO.
Stay connected with friends and family over the phone or video chat.
DON’T
Don’t leave your house or be in groups for non-essential purposes.
Don’t wear a facemask or gloves unless you are sick or caring for someone who is sick.
Don’t cough or sneeze into your hands.
Don’t gather information from unverified sources.
Don’t visit friends and family because you may put each other at greater risk.
</p>
</doc>