<doc docid='harvard_1' lang='eng' type='mono' source_url='https://drive.google.com/open?id=1O_8ts5-92PpFkT-B07yNiqjYWHBfL55Q'>
<p>
About COVID-19
Created by the COVID 19 Health Literacy Project in collaboration with Harvard Health Publishing
</p>
<p>
What is COVID-19? 
COVID 19 is a contagious respiratory illness.
This infection is caused by a new coronavirus that was first seen in Wuhan, China.
Many infected people have mild or no symptoms. 
Difficulty breathing, pneumonia, organ failure, and death can occur.
</p>
<p>
How does COVID-19 spread?
Person to person: You can become infected by breathing in an infected person’s cough or sneeze droplets from up to 6 feet away
Contaminated surfaces: You can become infected by touching contaminated surfaces and then touching your mouth, nose, or eyes. 
High risk surfaces include door handles, elevator buttons, counters, cellphones, and surfaces in common areas.
</p>
<p>
Can I get COVID-19?
Yes. You may have been exposed if:
You live with someone with COVID-19
You took care of someone with COVID-19
You were in contact with someone with COVID-19
You touched a contaminated surface or object
You may be more likely to get COVID 19 if you traveled recently, are a healthcare worker, or were in a place with many cases.
You are at risk for more serious symptoms if you have a weak immune system, heart disease, lung disease, or are older than 60.
</p>
<p>
What are the symptoms?
Common symptoms : dry cough, fever, shortness of breath
Less common symptoms : fatigue, muscle and joint pain, sore throat, headache.
</p>
<p>
How is COVID-19 different from the flu?
COVID 19 and the flu cause similar symptoms, but the viruses that cause these illnesses are different.
The virus causing COVID 19 spreads easily and is more likely to cause severe symptoms and death. 
Unlike the flu, these is currently no vaccine or drug to treat COVID-19.
</p>
<p>
How can I protect myself and others?
Avoid close contact or sharing personal items with people who are sick
Avoid touching your eyes, nose, and mouth
Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue, then throw the tissue in the trash
Clean surfaces and frequently touched objects
Wash your hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds or use a hand sanitizer containing at least 60% alcohol if soap and water are not available
Stay home and avoid being with people outside of your immediate family
</p>
<p>
What should I do if I feel sick?
Stay home and call your doctor. 
If you are having trouble breathing, suddenly feel drowsy or confused, or notice your lips or face turning blue, call 911.
Most people with mild symptoms can recover at home. 
If you must leave home to see a doctor, call beforehand and avoid public transport.
</p>
</doc>